# RASHI MAITHUL

### Erasmus Mundus Master's - Tourism Development & Culture (TourDC)

**♀** Lisbon, Portugal

**\** +91 9650884476/ +44 7448565477

@ maithulrashi19@gmail.com

in Rashi Maithul



### **EDUCATION**

Erasmus Mundus Joint Master Degree in Tourism Development & Culture (TourDc)

### **University of Glasgow**

m Sept 2020 - Dec 2020

**Q** Dumfries, Scotland

Erasmus Mundus Joint Master Degree in Tourism Development & Culture (TourDc)

### **University of Malta**

₩ Feb 2020 - July 2020

Malta

### Summer Workshop (TourDc)

### **University of Wageningen**

₩ July 2021

Netherlands

Erasmus Mundus Joint Master Degree in Tourism Development & Culture (TourDc)

### **University Institute of Lisbon**

m Sept 2021 - Sept 2022

**♀** Lisbon, Portugal

### Bachelor's in Tourism Management

College of Vocational Studies, University of Delhi

**2014** -2017

Oelhi, India

Advance Diploma in French Language

Kamla Nehru College, University of Delhi

**2016 - 2017** 

Oelhi, India

Remote

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Marketing & Strategy Development Intern (Part-Time)

### **Green Destinations** Ct 2021 - Present

- Developing marketing strategy for START program that aims to help destinations achieve their sustainability ambitions and overcome climate
  - challenges
- Developing Digital Marketing Strategy for Good Travel Guide
- Assisting with content creation for blog and social media channels
- Supporting Green Destination's partnership with India market
- Conducting competitive and competitor analysis

### Social Media Manager (Volunteer)

### **Erasmus Mundus Association**

Ct 2020 - Present

- Prussels, Belgium
- Contributing towards various EMA's projects, like
  - GENIE Platform
  - Diversity & Inclusion Video Series
  - Interconnected Project
- Manage & facilitate social media communities
- Create engaging multimedia content across multiple platforms

## SUMMARY

Experienced professional in Tourism Marketing, skilled in developing and implementing marketing strategies for high-budget online & offline tourism related campaigns. Recently represented University of Glasgow as the 2nd top team in the finale of **United National World Tourism** Organisation (UNWTO) student's competition for rural development.

## AREA OF EXPERTISE

Marketing Management & Communications

Public Relations

Market Research

Social Media Marketing

Strategic thinking

**Creative Thinking** 

Strong Work Ethic

**Critical Analysis** 

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Graphic Design Platform - CANVA

Microsoft Word & Powerpoint

Google Suite

## **COURSE MODULES**

- Marketing Management of Cultural Tourism
- Innovative Tourism Management Practices
- Environmental Communications
- Research Methods of Cultural Tourism
- Tourism Regional Development
- Large Events & Event Management
- Wine Tourism & Wine Business
- Tourism & Urban World

## LANGUAGES KNOWN

English | French | Hindi

## STRENGTHS

Committed and Flexibility

Teamwork

Consistent and Adaptable

Workaholic

Leadership & Good Communication Skills

Innovative, Creative & Proficient

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Business Development Manager

### **Representation World**

🛗 May 2019 - July 2020

New Delhi, India

- Developing growth strategies & plans for the organization
- Assist International Tourism Boards in developing & executing market plans
- Organizing networking events & training for international tourism boards
- Managing & retaining relationships with the trade partners
- Writing company press releases & getting it published
- Representing our organisation in Trade shows & networking events
- Managing social media channels & increasing engagement
- Creating monthly analytic reports and using them to develop effective marketing strategies
- Writing bid proposals for international Tourism boards

### Media Analyst (French Language)

### Prime Media and Opinion Analysis (Acquired by Wipro)

**Q** Gurugram, India

- Created reports after doing research & analysis of relevant print, online, broadcast & social media coverage for our clients
- Monitored corporate policies, products, industry & competitor trends for companies within this designated sector

### Travel Consultant (Trainee)

### **FCM Travel Solutions**

₩ June 2017 - Dec 2017

New Delhi, India

- Explored various potential tourist destinations
- Attended conferences to maintain familiarity with tourism trends
- Interacted with clients to understand their travel needs
- Prepared itineraries according to client's requirements
- Maintained relationship with tour operators & travel service providers
- Organized travel from beginning to end from booking travel tickets, accommodation, securing rental transportation

### Tour co-coordinator (Intern)

### **Delhi Tourism**

New Delhi, India

- Understanding and working toward development of Delhi as a tourist destination
- · Conducting Delhi City tours
- Interacted with clients to understand their travel needs
- Providing relevant information to tourists and assisting them during their visit to Delhi

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**



### **Erasmus Mundus Scholarship**

Recepient of prestigious Erasmus Mundus Joint Master Degree Program in Tourism Development & Culture (TourDC)



### **Global Competition**

Represented University of Glasgow in UNWTO's Student's League 2021 in Rural Development Competition



#### Scholastic Award

Awarded Merit Certificate on holding 2nd position in academics during Bachelors in Tourism Management at the college of vocational studies, University of Delhi

## **SOCIAL INVOLVEMENT**

- Attended destination training programme by Destination Canada and OTOAI (Outbound Tour Operators Association of India)
- Attended Ramayana Trail training programme organized by the High Commission of Sri Lanka.
- Attended South Asia's leading event & trade show for travel & tourism industry like SATTE-2020 India
- Volunteer at Comic-Con Delhi'16 for Every Flavor Geek)